[♪ opening theme song playing]
[door opens]
[HANA] Hi, I'm back.
[DERA] Welcome home, honey.
Tell me all about your day.
Less chitchat, more eat.
[groans]
Mm? Where's Yuru?
Not here right now.
He went looking for a place
to train.
Ken, Right, and Left
headed out with him.
Huh? And you're not afraid
he's going to run off
or get captured again?
It's cool,
Kotetsu tagged along.
I'm tracking their location.
-[Jiro whines]
-[HANA] Oh.
How was work? Stressful?
The Shaman was a pain
to bury, thanks to his size.
[DERA] Who do you think
killed him? The Kagemoris?
Meh.
I have no idea who did it
or why they'd even want to.
Well, who wanted you
to bury the body?
A couple of bandits.
And what did they say?
Not much.
Way they tell it,
they dropped by his shop
and found him very dead.
Could be connected to Yuru.
Perfect.
Possible, sure.
I just hope this doesn't mean
more trouble for us.
Mm?
Hold up.
These are the ingredients
I got ready
for hot pot last night.
You guys didn't eat it?
Nah, we figured we'd wait
and have it
whenever you got back.
So instead, we plowed through
some leftovers.
That's nice and all,
but you guys
didn't have to do that.
I know.
Yuru said hot pot's supposed
to be eaten together, though,
like a family.
[refrigerator door closes]
[HANA] Now, I'm just talking
to myself here.
There were some words
carved into the shaman's body.
"On the next full moon,
at the hour of the boar,
come to Fujimurayama
warehouse one.
I have your fake sister
and a child
from the village with me."
The note was addressed to Yuru.
The bandits told me
I shouldn't tell either of you
about the message,
so I'm definitely
not doing that now.
[Dera sighs]
[Hana sighs]
Whoever wrote it
is in on this mess.
They might even know
where Yuru's parents are.
I doubt it.
If they had his mom and dad,
they'd use them as hostages
to lure Yuru out into the open.
At the very least,
I don't think his parents
are being held by the person
who mutilated the shaman.
[Jiro whines]
That said,
they may have good intel.
This could be interesting.
I'm not sure
that's the word I'd use.
Okay, that's all from me.
I'm wiping my brain
and forgetting I saw anything.
Whatever happens next
is up to you.
[Dera groans]
What a pain in the ass
-this is turning out to be.
-[TV beeps]
-[TV chatter]
-So now what?
Wait, when's the hour
of the boar
on the next full moon?
Around 10:00 p.m.
on the 14th of this month.
[NEWSCASTER] In fact, you may...
For someone
who isn't getting involved,
you sure did your research.
[KEN] I'm not seeing
any place it would be okay
for us to practice archery.
[YURU] Me neither.
There are
way too many people around.
I know. One gust of wind
or a messed-up shot,
and we might hit somebody.
Perhaps Asa's daemons
could swallow us again.
No, thanks. Uh?
[panting]
[YURU] Ken, look!
These fish are huge.
Dinner!
Yuru, are you crazy?
Read the sign.
Fishing isn't allowed!
That's fine.
I can grab one
when it's in the shallows.
It's not about
the method you use.
It's just that I hoped
to find something
for Hana's hot pot.
And it's not about
your motives either.
[grunts] What's with this guy?
He's weirdly nice
for a barbarian.
Why don't people hunt here?
There's plenty of food.
If you know where to look.
Like those birds.
They'd be easy to catch.
Yeah, not a chance.
You can't hunt
everything you see.
Oh, right, Dera did mention
something about licenses.
Exactly, that's the law.
[YURU] It's also odd
that no one walks around
with a bow or a machete.
It's like they're asking
for some bandits to attack them.
Look, dude, we've got people
called "police officers"
to defend the public.
This isn't your village,
you know?
Kill somebody, and you'll get
arrested for murder,
even if you think you have
a good reason to do it.
[Yuru exclaims]
[KEN] What? Don't tell me.
That was a surprise?
Did no one teach him
the basic dos and don'ts
of living down here?
[gasps]
No normal person
would be caught dead
associating
with Higashi Village.
[KEN] Okay, then it falls on me
to set him straight.
Wait, that makes no sense.
You should be able
to protect yourself
if an enemy is out there
trying to murder you!
[breathes sharply] Sure,
but if you take it too far,
even self-defense
can turn into a crime.
[RIGHT] Huh?
[KOTETSU] Mm?
[RIGHT] Yuru, there be
daemons nearby.
-Are they hostile?
-[RIGHT] I know not.
[YURU] My weapons
aren't tested for battle yet,
so I'd like to avoid
unnecessary conflict.
We should leave.
-Right. As you command.
-[KEN] Uh?
Way to make
the smart call, Yuru!
♪
[panting]
[footsteps]
[LEFT] We're being followed.
And I suspect
they've sensed us as well.
[Ken exclaims]
[YURU] Who is it?
An ally or an enemy?
[dog panting]
[WOMAN] They're heading
to an isolated area.
[MAN] Did they notice us?
It took so long to find them.
[WOMAN]
We won't let them get away.
Our pursuers are approaching
quite conspicuously.
So do you think
they're after Yuru?
[YURU] Enough.
We'll take care of this here.
If they are enemies,
I'll be facing them
with an untested bow.
Ken, I might not be able
to protect you at all
in this fight.
[whimpers] I'll try not to die.
They approach.
Let us see who they are.
[dog panting]
[MAN] You're a master
and his daemons, aren't you?
[YURU] They're dressed in black.
Kagemoris?
I don't detect any bloodlust.
Still...
[HANA] What if I changed my mind
and decided to kill you?
It would be too late to escape.
[RIGHT] What do you want?
If I were you,
I'd answer carefully.
[WOMAN] Please relax!
[MAN]
You have the wrong idea!
We mean you no harm.
I swear it!
Here, we'll remove
our disguises.
Uh? Disguises?
[MAN]
We have to accompany
our master on walks,
or else they get harassed
or taken
to the animal control center.
[WOMAN]
So we pretend to be a couple
of regular pet owners
walking their dog.
We steal, um, I mean,
we borrow clothes and wigs
to look like humans.
[Ken gasps]
[dog pants]
This is what we look like
in our natural state.
Holy! For a second there,
I thought you two were
Tenaga-Ashinaga.
No, Yuru,
these are freaking aliens.
[BOTH] We're daemons.
For some reason,
people who can see us
always mistake us for aliens.
I find it extremely rude.
We're obviously
run-of-the-mill daemons.
All right, moving along.
What are we supposed
to call you?
-Uh?
-Yes, of course.
[speaking in fantasy language]
-Come again?
-[KEN] An alien language?
Ah...
[speaking in fantasy language]
The human tongue is unable
to pronounce their words.
I understand. Well,
that definitely makes sense.
[KEN] I'm totally staring
at extraterrestrials!
[FEMALE DAEMON]
Long, long ago in Noto,
the two of us were quietly
revered by human beings.
But as the centuries passed,
we were forgotten.
[MALE DAEMON] When the visitors
stopped coming,
well, we both thought
we would wither away
until nothing remained.
Luckily,
-a stray dog fell upon us.
-[dog whines]
[MALE DAEMON] And we entered
into a new contract by accident.
[YURU] What? You're saying
this dog is your master?
-That's right.
-[Ken gasps]
As such, we found ourselves
in a bit of a pickle.
We don't have names.
Can you believe it?
-Daemons serving a canine.
-[Yuru sighs]
You know,
I could introduce you
to somebody who can dissolve
your contract if you want.
Hold your tongue!
Please don't!
We're fine with this!
-[BOTH] No, no, no, no...
-[YURU] Uh, it looks as though
you're way more
than fine with it.
Actually, we're here because
you seem like daemons
we can come to for some advice.
The truth is,
we don't have anyone else
we can discuss
our unique situation with.
What do you say?
Is it possible you'd be willing
to be our friends?
Aye. That's fine.
Provided that you don't bring
any harm to our master.
[KEN] Buddy daemons?
-We would never!
-Wow! Amazing! Then may I ask
what our new best pals
are named?
-We're Right and Left.
-[both gasp]
[FEMALE DAEMON] What? No way!
The daemons
from Higashi Village? [laughs]
We've befriended
two absolute legends!
Please, may we
shake your hands?
I'm so happy to be alive!
It seems like you've got
a pretty cool master as well!
What's going on?
[Kotetsu groans]
Hey, uh, think you could
put your clothes back on?
It's kind of rude
to stand there naked.
-[female daemon gasps]
-[MALE DAEMON] Excuse us.
[YURU] Come to think of it.
Many daemons cover up,
even Tenaga-Ashinaga.
[KEN] At least they had
the barest amount
of social decency.
[YURU] Mm?
[dog panting]
Hmm.
-[RIGHT] Huh?
-[LEFT] Hm?
[wind blowing]
'Tis your lucky day.
-We have more friends coming.
-[FEMALE DAEMON] What?
[OSHIRASAMA]
Oh, divine guardians...
[Ken screams]
I found you.
Ah, Oshirasama.
To what do we owe the pleasure?
We thought you were residing
out in the countryside.
[FEMALE DAEMON]
Did he say Oshirasama?
-Two legends in one day?
-[male daemon cries]
[MALE DAEMON]
Her splendor is blinding!
Uh? Wait, Danji?
[Danji gasps] Yuru?
Oh, thank the gods.
[thuds]
I made it.
-[Danji grunts]
-Danji. Hey!
Why are you here?
It was awful.
The villagers got massacred!
-[Yuru gasps]
-[Right gasps]
[YURU] Again?
[DANJI] Our home might never
be able to recover.
[YURU] How could this happen?
I'm down the mountain.
There's no point
in attacking them now!
Asa wouldn't have forced
the barrier open again either.
-So that means...
-[Danji sniffles]
[YURU] Who attacked the village?
It had to have been
someone else this time.
[DANJI] I think you're right.
I only saw him from a distance,
but it was just one guy.
He killed all of them
with a pair of katanas.
Dozens of adults
were slaughtered.
I think the village
may really be doomed.
My ma told me to run.
To come down here
to protect you.
I ran into Oshirasama
as soon as I got outside.
Whose order did you say it was?
[DANJI] Huh?
It was my mom.
But it's not just her.
I've been worried too--
-[YURU] Wait.
-[Danji gasps]
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Before we go any further,
I have one thing
I need to confirm.
Danji, no more lies.
You're not a human, are you?
[Danji breathes shakily]
You're a daemon.
♪
What?
Did I slip up?
[YURU]
You're not casting a shadow.
[Danji exhales]
[YURU] Left and Right,
Kotetsu, Jiro...
every daemon I've met
had one thing in common.
Not one of them cast a shadow.
Everything else down here does.
It's automatic.
But not you,
because daemons
aren't able to, are they?
[Danji breathes shakily]
[YURU] All this time,
you've lied to me, too.
-Yeah?
-Yeah, check it out yourself.
Our bar has the cutest girls
in town!
Uh?
Hey, Jin! Haruo!
It's nice to see you.
So you've been holding up
all right, Aoi?
[AOI] I have,
thanks to you, Jin!
That stalker...
Haven't caught a glimpse of him
since that night!
Well, that's good to hear.
He was such a creeper.
How did you make him stop?
Did you beat him up
or something?
[JIN] That's not my style.
Let's say he's sleeping
with the fishes.
[Aoi chuckles] Oh, please!
You're such a jokester, Jin!
-Anyway.
-Right. To business.
That Tadera guy showed up.
We brought him to the back,
-like you asked.
-[beeps]
[DERA] Jin, buddy, what gives?
You really think
this is the right way
to treat a guest?
Come on, you tell me to come
to a place with pretty girls.
So why am I not
with all the pretty girls?
We don't serve the likes of you.
Enjoy our finest roast.
[Dera grunts softly]
[JIN] We won't give you
any alcohol,
but how about an apology?
The other day,
some of our agents
were tailing you.
Yep, the old lady's group
and that butterfly.
That decision wasn't made
by the clan proper.
It goes without saying
that Asa didn't know
and wasn't involved.
Some of our members
felt the need to grandstand.
My apologies.
Gotta say,
you're a serious dude.
I have little regard
for the law,
but I do prefer to keep my word
whenever possible.
Enough said.
Consider yourself forgiven.
Now, I assume you're here
because you have information
to share?
Sort of.
More like we've got a problem.
And you're up.
[Jin grunts]
[DANJI] My shadow...
How could I forget?
I am able to make one,
if I want to.
I was just so relieved
to see you again,
it had slipped my mind.
We played together
as little kids.
I don't remember a time
before you.
And now...
there's this.
You had me fooled
for even longer
than the Asa in that cell.
♪
And if you are a daemon,
you must have another half.
[DANJI] You know my other half.
Really well, actually.
[YURU] Uh?
The fake Asa.
That's right.
The girl you called sister
and I
are a pair of child daemons.
And this is my true form.
[Ken gasps]
A little boy and girl,
Zashiki-Warashi.
[GRAND DAUGHTER]
Hello? Hey, Gran!
Where's Oshirasama?
They said they were taking
a trip to Tokyo.
What? That's awesome! Lucky.
And they took a friend
along with them.
Such a kind lad.
Seemed like a Zashiki-Warashi.
Oh, no! What house
were they from?
I couldn't say.
A long time ago, you'd find them
all over the place.
But when they leave a house,
isn't that bad luck?
So does that mean
their house is doomed?
Some old legends
make that claim.
Although, if you were to ask me
it's not them leaving
that causes the home to fall.
I'll bet
it's the other way around.
And when a household begins
to slip into disrepair,
their soft little hearts
just can't take it.
And their masters don't want
to see them sad anymore,
so they'll either
end their contract
or they'll agree to walk away
from the house hand-in-hand.
Ideally.
Losing one's home is heavy.
I couldn't put the entire blame
on their bitty shoulders.
[RIGHT] What's this, Yuru?
You only just now noticed
your friend is a daemon?
[YURU] What does that mean?
Oh, yeah, you two were the ones
watching over the village,
so you must've seen
Danji plenty of times!
You knew he was
a daemon all along,
and didn't wanna tell me?
You've both been lying
to me, too?
Hold on, the two of you
played together nearly every day
since you were wee lads!
We assumed you deduced
his true nature
and kept him as your companion
in spite of that.
It never even occurred to us
you might not know
something so fundamental
about your closest friend.
-Apologies.
-[YURU] Uh?
I thought...
No, this one is on me, guys.
I'm sorry for doubting you.
I'll say...
we have always wondered
about your other half.
That she was kept in a cell
certainly clarifies things.
[LEFT] We sensed her presence.
Never seeing her
made us concerned.
[footsteps]
[Danji (tsugai) gasps]
Tell me, who is your master?
Who used that fake Asa
to bind me to our village?
Who's the one that ordered you
to follow me around
and act as a spy?
I am not a spy!
I swear to you,
it's not like that.
You will not fool me again.
Back then, you'd always ask me
to take you with me
when I went into the mountains
to hunt. [grunts]
I know why!
You were hoping to kill me!
So you and the rest
of the villagers
could get your hands on Seal!
-I wasn't!
-I'll bet those bandits
were sent by you too,
weren't they?
I wouldn't!
[YURU] So who is your master?
Who's giving you your orders?
Is it Granny Yamaha?
[Danji (tsugai) gasps]
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
You're wrong.
You know my master.
She's the same woman
I've always called my mom.
[Yuru breathes shakily]
So it's Kyoka?
[DANJI (TSUGAI)] Yes.
Instead of calling her Master,
we were told to call her Mom.
To act the same
as a child would
with their mother.
She gave me a mission,
to watch over you.
My other half,
the one in the cage,
was given a different mission.
Pretend to be Asa
and protect Granny Yamaha
if needed.
So yes, I wanted to follow you
up the mountain.
Because I wanted to protect you
from those bandits.
I know it might be hard
to believe me...
[DANJI]...but it's the truth.
[Yuru breathes shakily]
[YURU] Kyoka too?
Was everyone lying?
That's it.
There's not a soul
in the village I can trust.
They all want me dead.
[Danji breathes uneasily]
[wind blowing]
[Yuru inhales, sighs]
Right, Left? Ken?
I need you to wait here.
I'd like some time
in the mountains by myself.
But if you're all
by your lonesome,
and disaster strikes,
what then?
No, please, Right.
I just need to be alone.
[Right grunts]
If our master bids us to stay,
we will.
We won't argue,
but ask that you not stray far
in your search for solitude.
[Yuru exhales]
[Ken breathes softly]
[footsteps receding]
[dog panting]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[YURU] Between bandits,
beasts, and nature itself,
the threat of death is
ever present in the mountains.
That made things simple.
Just focus on survival.